<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<Collections>
  <BloomFilter>
    <DirectConstructor>
      <summary>
        Initializes an empty <see cref="BloomFilter{T}"/> with the given size.
      </summary>
      <param name="bitCount">The number of bits in the bloom filter. This value will be rounded up to the nearest 32 or 64 bits.</param>
      <param name="maxHashCount">
        The maximum number of hash functions to use from the <paramref name="hashProvider"/>. If the
        hash provider does not support this many hash functions, fewer will be used.
      </param>
      <remarks>
        It is recommended to use the <see cref="BloomFilter{T}(int,float)"/> constructor, which will calculate an appropriate
        size for the bloom filter based on a desired false positive rate.
      </remarks>
    </DirectConstructor>
    <TuningConstructor>
      <summary>
        Initializes an empty <see cref="BloomFilter{T}" /> that should approximate the given false positive rate for the given
        number of items.
      </summary>
      <param name="itemCount">The approximate number of items that will be added to the set.</param>
      <param name="falsePositiveRate">The desired false positive rate, as a number from 0 to 1 (exclusive).</param>
      <param name="hashProvider">
        The <see cref="IMultiHashProvider{T}"/> that provides the hash codes for the items added to the
        set, or null to use a default hash code provider that works reasonably well for most types.
      </param>
      <param name="maxHashCount">
        The maximum number of hash functions to use, or 0 to use the number that produces the smallest filter for the given false
        positive rate. It is recommended to simply pass 0, allowing an optimal Bloom filter to be constructed but if you want to
        improve the speed, you can limit the number of hash functions. The filter may use more memory as a result. Do not use
        fewer than three hash functions, as it will cause memory consumption to rise dramatically. (For instance, using only one
        hash function may cause memory usage to be 100 or 1000 times what it otherwise would be, or more, depending on the false
        positive rate.) Even three hash functions may cause memory consumption to be 3 or 5 or 10 the normal amount.
        In general, as the false positive rate decreases, more hash functions are needed.
      </param>
      <remarks>
        As more items are added to the set, the false positive rate increases. This constructor attempts to construct a
        filter that will have the given false positive rate after the given number of items have been added. The Bloom filter is
        usually capable of achieving the false positive rate or better, but sometimes it may exceed it slightly, especially with
        small numbers of items. If you have strict requirements for the false positive rate, you should perform testing to see
        how it performs with your data.
      </remarks>
    </TuningConstructor>
  </BloomFilter>

  <CollectionBase>
    <ClearItems>
      <summary>Called when the collection is being cleared. The base implementation actually clears the list.</summary>
    </ClearItems>
    <InsertItem>
      <summary>
        Called when a new item is being inserted into the collection. The base implementation actually performs the insertion.
      </summary>
    </InsertItem>
    <RemoveItem>
      <summary>
        Called when an item is being removed from the collection. The base implementation actually performs the removal.
      </summary>
    </RemoveItem>
    <SetItem>
      <summary>
        Called when an item in the collection is being assigned. The base implementation actually performs the assignment.
      </summary>
    </SetItem>
    <OnCollectionChanged>
      <summary>Called when the collection may have been changed by the user.</summary>
    </OnCollectionChanged>
  </CollectionBase>

  <Common>
    <Clear>
      <summary>Removes all items from the collection.</summary>
    </Clear>
    <Contains>
      <summary>Determines whether the collection contains the given item.</summary>
    </Contains>
    <CopyTo>
      <summary>Copies all items from the collection to the array at the given index.</summary>
    </CopyTo>
    <GetEnumerator>
      <summary>Allocates and returns an <see cref="IEnumerator{T}" /> to iterate through the items in the collection.</summary>
    </GetEnumerator>
    <IndexOf>
      <summary>Returns the first index of the given item, or -1 if the item does not exist in the collection.</summary>
    </IndexOf>
    <Indexer>
      <summary>Gets the item from the list at the given index.</summary>
    </Indexer>
    <Insert>
      <summary>Inserts an item into the collection at a given index.</summary>
    </Insert>
    <Remove>
      <summary>
        Removes the first instance of the given item from the collection if it exists. Returns true if an item was removed.
      </summary>
    </Remove>
    <RemoveAt>
      <summary>Removes the item at the given index.</summary>
    </RemoveAt>
    <ToArray>
      <summary>Creates and returns an array containing all of the items in the collection.</summary>
    </ToArray>
  </Common>

  <Dictionary>
    <Contains>
      <summary>Determines whether the dictionary contains the given <see cref="KeyValuePair{K,V}" />.</summary>
    </Contains>
    <ContainsKey>
      <summary>Determines whether the dictionary contains the given key.</summary>
    </ContainsKey>
    <CopyTo>
      <summary>
        Copies all of the keys and values in the dictionary to an array in the form of <see cref="KeyValuePair{K,V}" /> objects.
      </summary>
    </CopyTo>
    <GetEnumerator>
      <summary>
        Returns an enumerator that iterates through the keys and values in the dictionary, in the form of
        <see cref="KeyValuePair{K,V}" /> objects.
      </summary>
    </GetEnumerator>
    <Indexer>
      <summary>Returns the item with the given key, or throws an exception if they key does not exist in the dictionary.</summary>
    </Indexer>
    <Keys>
      <summary>Gets a collection containing the keys within the dictionary.</summary>
    </Keys>
    <ToArray>
      <summary>
        Returns an array containing all of the keys and values in the dictionary in the form of <see cref="KeyValuePair{K,V}" />
        objects.
      </summary>
    </ToArray>
    <TryGetValue>
      <summary>
        Attempts to retrieve the value with the given key. Returns true if the value could be retrieved and false if the key
        does not exist in the dictionary.
      </summary>
    </TryGetValue>
    <Values>
      <summary>
        Gets a collection containing the values within the dictionary. Values may be included in the collection multiple times,
        if they are referenced by multiple keys.
      </summary>
    </Values>
  </Dictionary>

  <MultiHashProvider>
    <HashCount>
      <summary>Gets the number of distinct hash functions supported.</summary>
    </HashCount>
    <GetHashCode>
      <summary>Gets a hash code for an item.</summary>
      <param name="hashFunction">The number of the hash function to use, from 0 to <see cref="HashCount"/>-1.</param>
      <param name="item">The item to hash.</param>
      <returns>A hash value. Negative hash values are supported.</returns>
    </GetHashCode>
  </MultiHashProvider>

  <Queue>
    <TryDequeue>
      <summary>
        Attempts to remove an item from the queue. True is returned if an item was successfully removed (and stored in
        <paramref name="item"/>) and false if an item was not removed because the queue was empty.
      </summary>
    </TryDequeue>
  </Queue>
  
  <ValidatedCollection>
    <ValidateItem>
      <summary>
        Called when an item is about to be inserted or set, to check the validity of the new item. The method should throw an
        exception if the item is not valid.
      </summary>
    </ValidateItem>
  </ValidatedCollection>
</Collections>