<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<Collections>
  <CollectionBase>
    <ClearItems>
      <summary>Called when the collection is being cleared. The base implementation actually clears the list.</summary>
    </ClearItems>
    <InsertItem>
      <summary>
        Called when a new item is being inserted into the collection. The base implementation actually performs the insertion.
      </summary>
    </InsertItem>
    <RemoveItem>
      <summary>
        Called when an item is being removed from the collection. The base implementation actually performs the removal.
      </summary>
    </RemoveItem>
    <SetItem>
      <summary>
        Called when an item in the collection is being assigned. The base implementation actually performs the assignment.
      </summary>
    </SetItem>
    <OnCollectionChanged>
      <summary>Called when the collection may have been changed by the user.</summary>
    </OnCollectionChanged>
  </CollectionBase>

  <Common>
    <Clear>
      <summary>Removes all items from the collection.</summary>
    </Clear>
    <Contains>
      <summary>Determines whether the collection contains the given item.</summary>
    </Contains>
    <CopyTo>
      <summary>Copies all items from the collection to the array at the given index.</summary>
    </CopyTo>
    <GetEnumerator>
      <summary>Allocates and returns an <see cref="IEnumerator{T}" /> to iterate through the items in the collection.</summary>
    </GetEnumerator>
    <IndexOf>
      <summary>Returns the first index of the given item, or -1 if the item does not exist in the collection.</summary>
    </IndexOf>
    <Indexer>
      <summary>Gets the item from the list at the given index.</summary>
    </Indexer>
    <Insert>
      <summary>Inserts an item into the collection at a given index.</summary>
    </Insert>
    <Remove>
      <summary>
        Removes the first instance of the given item from the collection if it exists. Returns true if an item was removed.
      </summary>
    </Remove>
    <RemoveAt>
      <summary>Removes the item at the given index.</summary>
    </RemoveAt>
    <ToArray>
      <summary>Creates and returns an array containing all of the items in the collection.</summary>
    </ToArray>
  </Common>

  <Dictionary>
    <Contains>
      <summary>Determines whether the dictionary contains the given <see cref="KeyValuePair{K,V}" />.</summary>
    </Contains>
    <ContainsKey>
      <summary>Determines whether the dictionary contains the given key.</summary>
    </ContainsKey>
    <CopyTo>
      <summary>
        Copies all of the keys and values in the dictionary to an array in the form of <see cref="KeyValuePair{K,V}" /> objects.
      </summary>
    </CopyTo>
    <GetEnumerator>
      <summary>
        Returns an enumerator that iterates through the keys and values in the dictionary, in the form of
        <see cref="KeyValuePair{K,V}" /> objects.
      </summary>
    </GetEnumerator>
    <Indexer>
      <summary>Returns the item with the given key, or throws an exception if they key does not exist in the dictionary.</summary>
    </Indexer>
    <Keys>
      <summary>Gets a collection containing the keys within the dictionary.</summary>
    </Keys>
    <ToArray>
      <summary>
        Returns an array containing all of the keys and values in the dictionary in the form of <see cref="KeyValuePair{K,V}" />
        objects.
      </summary>
    </ToArray>
    <TryGetValue>
      <summary>
        Attempts to retrieve the value with the given key. Returns true if the value could be retrieved and false if the key
        does not exist in the dictionary.
      </summary>
    </TryGetValue>
    <Values>
      <summary>
        Gets a collection containing the values within the dictionary. Values may be included in the collection multiple times,
        if they are referenced by multiple keys.
      </summary>
    </Values>
  </Dictionary>

  <ValidatedCollection>
    <ValidateItem>
      <summary>
        Called when an item is about to be inserted or set, to check the validity of the new item. The method should throw an
        exception if the item is not valid.
      </summary>
    </ValidateItem>
  </ValidatedCollection>
</Collections>