<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<Security>
  <Common>
    <Exception>
      <Cons0>
        <summary>Initializes a new exception.</summary>
      </Cons0>

      <Cons1>
        <summary>Initializes a new exception.</summary>
        <param name="message">A human-readable message that describes the error.</param>
      </Cons1>

      <Cons2>
        <summary>Initializes a new exception.</summary>
        <param name="message">A human-readable message that describes the error.</param>
        <param name="innerException">The exception that is the cause of the current exception.</param>
      </Cons2>
    </Exception>

    <ToString>Converts the object to a human-readable string.</ToString>
  </Common>
  
  <ReadOnlyClass>
    <Finish>
      <summary>
        Validates and locks the property values of the object so that they cannot be changed. This method is
        intended to be called by the PGP interface before returning the object to the user.
      </summary>
    </Finish>
  </ReadOnlyClass>

  <Key>
    <Keyring>
      <summary>
        Gets or sets the name of the keyring file that contains the key, or null if they key is from the default
        keyring.
      </summary>
    </Keyring>
  </Key>

  <PGPSystem>
    <Decrypt>
      <summary>Decrypts the given ciphertext and writes the result to the given destination.</summary>
    </Decrypt>
    
    <DeleteKey>
      <summary>Deletes the given key, or a part of it, from its keyring.</summary>
    </DeleteKey>

    <Encrypt>
      <summary>Encrypts the given source data, writing the result to the given destination.</summary>
    </Encrypt>
    
    <ExportPublicKeys>
      <summary>Exports the given public keys to the given destination.</summary>
    </ExportPublicKeys>
    
    <ExportPublicKeys2>
      <summary>Exports all public keys in the given keyring files and/or the default keyring to the given destination.</summary>
      <param name="keyrings">
        Specifies a list of additional keyrings. If null or empty, no additional keyrings will be used.
      </param>
      <param name="includeDefaultKeyring">
        Specifies whether the default keyring will be implicitly included. If false,
        only the keyrings listed in <paramref name="keyrings"/> will be used.
      </param>
      <param name="options">Options controlling how the keys should be exported.</param>
      <param name="destination">The stream to which the key data will be written.</param>
      <param name="format">The output format.</param>
    </ExportPublicKeys2>
    
    <ExportSecretKeys>
      <summary>Exports the given secret keys to the given destination.</summary>
    </ExportSecretKeys>
    
    <ExportSecretKeys2>
      <summary>Exports all secret keys in the given keyring files and/or the default keyring to the given destination.</summary>
      <param name="keyrings">
        Specifies a list of additional keyrings. If null or empty, no additional keyrings will be used.
      </param>
      <param name="includeDefaultKeyring">
        Specifies whether the default keyring will be implicitly included. If false,
        only the keyrings listed in <paramref name="keyrings"/> will be used.
      </param>
      <param name="options">Options controlling how the keys should be exported.</param>
      <param name="destination">The stream to which the key data will be written.</param>
      <param name="format">The output format.</param>
    </ExportSecretKeys2>
    
    <GenerateRandomData>
      <summary>Generates random data and writes it to the given buffer.</summary>
      <param name="level">
        The level of randomness of the data. For most operations, this should be
        <see cref="Randomness.Strong"/>.
      </param>
      <param name="buffer">The array to which the random data will be written.</param>
      <param name="index">
        The index within <paramref name="buffer"/> where writing will begin.
      </param>
      <param name="count">The number of bytes to write.</param>
    </GenerateRandomData>

    <GetPassword>
      <summary>Gets the password for the key named in the given password hint.</summary>
      <param name="keyId">The ID of the key whose password is sought.</param>
      <param name="passwordHint">A password hint to be displayed to the user.</param>
      <returns>Returns a new <see cref="SecureString"/> containing the password.</returns>
      <remarks>The password will be disposed after being used.</remarks>
    </GetPassword>

    <GetPublicKeys>
      <summary>Gets all public keys in the default keyring.</summary>
    </GetPublicKeys>
    
    <GetPublicKeys2>
      <summary>Gets all public keys in the default keyring and/or the list of keyring files.</summary>
      <param name="signatures">Specifies whether key signatures should be returned and verified.</param>
      <param name="keyrings">
        Specifies a list of additional keyring. If null or empty, no additional keyrings will be used.
      </param>
      <param name="includeDefaultKeyring">
        Specifies whether the default keyring will be implicitly included. If false,
        only the keyrings listed in <paramref name="keyrings"/> will be used.
      </param>
    </GetPublicKeys2>
    
    <GetSecretKeys>
      <summary>Gets all secret keys in the default keyring.</summary>
    </GetSecretKeys>
    
    <GetSecretKeys2>
      <summary>Gets all secret keys in the default keyring and/or the list of keyring files.</summary>
      <param name="keyrings">
        Specifies a list of additional keyring. If null or empty, no additional keyrings will be used.
      </param>
      <param name="includeDefaultKeyring">
        Specifies whether the default keyring will be implicitly included. If false,
        only the keyrings listed in <paramref name="keyrings"/> will be used.
      </param>
    </GetSecretKeys2>

    <GetSupportedCiphers>
      <summary>
        Gets a list of the cipher algorithms supported by the PGP system. You can use them case-insensitively to
        check whether a given algorithm is supported.
      </summary>
    </GetSupportedCiphers>

    <GetSupportedCompressions>
      <summary>
        Gets a list of the compression algorithms supported by the PGP system. You can use them
        case-insensitively to check whether a given algorithm is supported.
      </summary>
    </GetSupportedCompressions>

    <GetSupportedHashes>
      <summary>
        Gets a list of the hash algorithms supported by the PGP system. You can use them case-insensitively to
        check whether a given algorithm is supported.
      </summary>
    </GetSupportedHashes>

    <GetSupportedKeyTypes>
      <summary>
        Gets a list of the key types supported by the PGP system. You can use them case-insensitively to check
        whether a given key type is supported.
      </summary>
    </GetSupportedKeyTypes>
    
    <Hash>
      <summary>Generates a hash of the given data, using the given hash algorithm.</summary>
      <param name="hashAlgorithm">
        The name of the algorithm used to hash the data. This can be one of the
        <see cref="HashAlgorithm"/> values, or another algorithm name. If you don't particularly care which algorithm
        will be used, then it's usually best to use <see cref="HashAlgorithm.Default"/>. If you do want to use a specific
        algorithm, you should check that it is supported by checking <see cref="GetSupportedHashes"/>.
      </param>
      <param name="data">The stream from which the data to hash will be read.</param>
    </Hash>

    <ImportKeys2>
      <summary>Imports keys from the given source into the default keyring.</summary>
    </ImportKeys2>
    
    <ImportKeys3>
      <summary>Imports keys from the given source into the given keyring.</summary>
    </ImportKeys3>

    <OnInvalidPassword>
      <summary>
        Called when the password for the given key is invalid, to allow client applications to flush their
        password cache (if using one) and retry. Applications should not request a new password in response to this
        event.
      </summary>
      <param name="keyId">The key ID whose password was invalid.</param>
    </OnInvalidPassword>
    
    <Sign>
      <summary>Signs the given source data and writes the result to the given destination.</summary>
    </Sign>

    <SignAndEncrypt>
      <summary>Signs and/or encrypts the given source data and writes the result to the given destination.</summary>
      <param name="sourceData">The stream from which the unencrypted source data will be read.</param>
      <param name="destination">The stream to which the signed and/or encrypted data will be written.</param>
      <param name="signingOptions">Options that control the signing of the data, or null to only encrypt the data.</param>
      <param name="encryptionOptions">Options that control the encryption of the data, or null to only sign the data.</param>
      <param name="outputOptions">Options that control the output format.</param>
      <remarks>
        Only one of <paramref name="signingOptions"/> and <paramref name="encryptionOptions"/> can be null.
      </remarks>
    </SignAndEncrypt>

    <Verify2>
      <summary>Verifies embedded signatures in the given signed data. The signed data should not have been
        simultaneously encrypted. To verify signatures in encrypted, signed data, call <see cref="Decrypt"/>.
      </summary>
    </Verify2>

    <Verify3>
      <summary>
        Verifies detached signatures for the given signed data. The signed data should not have been
        simultaneously encrypted. To verify signatures in encrypted, signed data, call <see cref="Decrypt"/>.
      </summary>
    </Verify3>
  </PGPSystem>
</Security>