<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<TX>
  <STM>
    <Allocate>
      <exception cref="NotSupportedException">Thrown if <typeparamref name="T"/> is not cloneable. See
        <see cref="TransactionalVariable{T}"/> for more details.
      </exception>
    </Allocate>
    <CheckConsistency>
      <summary>
        Checks that the current transaction has seen a consistent view of memory up to the point when this method was
        called.
      </summary>
      <exception cref="TransactionAbortedException">
        Thrown if any variables have changed since they were read by the transaction
        in such a way that restarting the transaction would allow it to see different values.
      </exception>
      <include file="documentation.xml" path="TX/STM/ConsistencyCheckRemarks/*" />
    </CheckConsistency>
    <Commit>
      <summary>
        Checks that the transaction has seen a consistent view of memory and then commits any changes that the
        transaction has made.
      </summary>
      <remarks>In the case of a nested transaction, the changes will be added to the enclosing transaction, and will be committed
        when the enclosing transaction is committed.
      </remarks>
      <exception cref="InvalidOperationException">
        Thrown if the transaction has already finished (i.e. been committed, rolled back, etc), or if this is not the topmost
        transaction on the transaction stack.
      </exception>
      <exception cref="TransactionAbortedException">
        Thrown if the attempt to commit the transaction failed because of a conflict with another transaction.
      </exception>
    </Commit>
    <ConsistencyCheckRemarks>
      <include file="documentation.xml" path="TX/STM/ConsistencyRemarks/*" />
      <remarks>
        <para>
          This method will deliberately fail to detect inconsistency in the case that this is a nested transaction and the
          inconsistency can only be resolved by restarting an enclosing transaction. In that case, aborting the nested
          transaction could lead to an infinite loop where the transaction restarts but can never escape the inconsistency.
          This type of inconsistency should be "safe" in that it should not impact the behavior of the nested transaction, so
          the nested transaction will be allowed to commit successfully, but the enclosing transaction will eventually abort.
        </para>
        <para>
          Calling this method can incur a significant performance penalty. If inconsistency would merely lead to the transaction
          throwing an exception, it would be better to take the optimistic approach of avoiding the consistency check and
          catching the exception. If the exception can be thrown either due to user error or to inconsistency, then in the
          exception handler you can call <see cref="IsConsistent" /> to see if the transaction has seen a consistent view of
          memory. If so, the exception can be assumed to be due to user error, and if not, the transaction can be retried. The
          <see cref="STM.Retry" /> method implements this logic for you.
        </para>
      </remarks>
    </ConsistencyCheckRemarks>
    <ConsistencyRemarks>
      <remarks>
        It is possible for a transaction to see an inconsistent view of memory. See the following example:
        <code>
using(STMTransaction tx = STMTransaction.Create())
{
  a = var1.Read();
  // another transaction commits changes to <c>var1</c> and <c>var2</c> at this point
  b = var2.Read();
  ...
}
        </code>
        In this example, the transaction will see a value of <c>var1</c> from before the other transaction committed, and a
        value of <c>var2</c> from after it committed. The values will be inconsistent. When the transaction in the example calls
        <see cref="STMTransaction.Commit"/>, the inconsistency will be detected and the transaction will be aborted, but until
        that point, if the transaction in the example is not written with this possibility in mind, the inconsistency may cause
        it to behave unexpectedly. If your algorithm requires consistency, you can call <see cref="CheckConsistency"/> or
        <see cref="IsConsistent" /> any time to validate the consistency of the transaction, or you can use the
        <see cref="STMOptions.EnsureConsistency" /> option, but see their documentation for proper usage.
      </remarks>
    </ConsistencyRemarks>
    <IsConsistent>
      <summary>
        Determines whether the transaction has seen a consistent view of memory up to the point when this method is
        called.
      </summary>
      <seealso cref="CheckConsistency"/>
      <include file="documentation.xml" path="TX/STM/ConsistencyCheckRemarks/*" />
    </IsConsistent>
    <NewTVar>
      <include file="documentation.xml" path="TX/STM/TVarRemarks/*" />
      <exception cref="NotSupportedException"> Thrown if <typeparamref name="T"/> is not cloneable.</exception>
    </NewTVar>
    <OpenForWrite>
      <summary>
        Opens the variable for read/write access and returns the current value. This method is meant to be used when the
        variable's value needs to be read before writing it, or when it is an object whose methods and properties will be used to
        mutate it. To replace the value completely, call <see cref="Set"/>.
      </summary>
      <exception cref="InvalidOperationException">
        Thrown if there is no active <see cref="STMTransaction"/> on this thread, or
        if the current value's implementation of <see cref="ICloneable"/> is incorrect.
      </exception>
    </OpenForWrite>
    <Read>
      <summary>
        Opens the variable for read access and returns the current value. If there is no current transaction, this is
        equivalent to calling <see cref="ReadWithoutOpening"/>. You must not call any methods or properties on the returned object
        that would change it, without opening it in read/write mode (by calling <see cref="OpenForWrite"/>) first!
      </summary>
    </Read>
    <ReadWithoutOpening>
      <summary>
        Reads the value of this variable without opening it. This should only be done if the logic will not be affected by
        the variable's value changing after it's read, or if you want to check a variable's value without affecting the current
        transaction (e.g. to view it for debugging purposes). If there is no current transaction, the most recently committed
        value will returned.
      </summary>
    </ReadWithoutOpening>
    <Retry>
      <param name="options"><see cref="STMOptions" /> to use when creating the transaction.</param>
      <remarks>If <see cref="TransactionAbortedException"/> is thrown from the delegate, it will cause the transaction to be
      restarted. If another type of exception is thrown, a consistency check will be done. If the transaction is consistent,
      the exception will be considered to be legitimate and will be rethrown. If the consistency check fails, the exception will
      be assumed to be caused by the inconsistency, and the transaction will be restarted.
      </remarks>
    </Retry>
    <RetryWithTimeout>
      <param name="timeoutMs">The amount of time, in milliseconds, before the method will stop retrying the code. If
        <see cref="Timeout.Infinite"/> is given, the method will only stop when the delegate succeeds.
      </param>
      <param name="options"><see cref="STMOptions" /> to use when creating the transaction.</param>
      <remarks>
        If <see cref="TransactionAbortedException"/> is thrown from the delegate, it will cause the transaction to be
        restarted. If another type of exception is thrown, a consistency check will be done. If the transaction is consistent,
        the exception will be considered to be legitimate and will be rethrown. If the consistency check fails, the exception
        will be assumed to be caused by the inconsistency, and the transaction will be restarted. If the method times out,
        <see cref="TransactionAbortedException"/> will be thrown. The timeout will not interrupt the delegate while it's running,
        and will only be checked when it aborts the transaction, so this method may run for longer than the timeout specifies.
      </remarks>
      <exception cref="TransactionAbortedException">Thrown if the timeout expired before the action was able to complete
        successfully.
      </exception>
    </RetryWithTimeout>
    <Set>
      <summary>
        Opens the variable for writing and sets its value to the given value. This method is meant to be used when the
        variable's value will be replaced completely. To alter a mutable object through its methods and properties, use
        <see cref="OpenForWrite"/> to return the current instance of it.
      </summary>
      <exception cref="InvalidOperationException">
        Thrown if there is no active <see cref="STMTransaction"/> on this thread, or
        if the current value's implementation of <see cref="ICloneable"/> is incorrect.
      </exception>
    </Set>
    <TVarRemarks>
      <remarks>
        All types used in a <see cref="TransactionalVariable{T}" /> must be thread-safe for reading.
        If a transaction calls <see cref="OpenForWrite" /> and then mutates the returned value, the change to the instance must
        be isolated from other transactions. The way it does this depends on the type of the value.
        <list type="bullet">
          <item>
            <description>
              Immutable types are shared across all transactions. You can designate a type as immutable by marking it with the
              <see cref="STMImmutableAttribute" />, but you must ensure the type is actually immutable. If an immutable type
              implements <see cref="ICloneable" />, the implementation will be ignored
            </description>
          </item>
          <item>
            <description>
              Value types that contain no references to mutable reference types are copied bitwise if necessary.
              You can customize the copying process by implementing <see cref="ICloneable" />, but this is rarely necessary.
            </description>
          </item>
          <item>
            <description>
              Mutable reference types and value types that contain mutable reference types cannot be handled automatically by the
              system, and must implement <see cref="ICloneable" />. Types that do not implement it cannot be used within a
              <see cref="TransactionalVariable{T}" /> and will cause the constructor to throw a
              <see cref="NotSupportedException" />.
            </description>
          </item>
        </list>
      </remarks>
    </TVarRemarks>
  </STM>
</TX>