<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>

<UI>
  <Common>
    <Dispose>
      <summary>Releases unmanaged resources held by the object.</summary>
    </Dispose>
    
    <Dispose1>
      <summary>Releases unmanaged resources held by the object.</summary>
      <param name="finalizing">Indicates whether the object is currently being finalized.</param>
    </Dispose1>

    <Equals>
      <summary>Returns true if the given object is equal to this one, and false if not.</summary>
    </Equals>
    
    <GetHashCode>
      <summary>Gets a hash code for the object.</summary>  
    </GetHashCode>

    <OpEquals>
      <summary>Returns true if the two objects are equal, and false if not.</summary>
    </OpEquals>

    <OpNotEquals>
      <summary>Returns false if the two objects are equal, and true if not.</summary>
    </OpNotEquals>

    <ToString>
      <summary>Returns a human-readable description of the object.</summary>
    </ToString>

    <TrimExcess>
      <summary>Removes unused space within the object.</summary>
    </TrimExcess>
  </Common>

  <ChangeEvent>
    <Do>
      <summary>Performs the change.</summary>
      <exception cref="InvalidOperationException">
        Thrown if the change has already been applied, or if the document has
        been altered such that the change cannot be applied.
      </exception>
    </Do>

    <Undo>
      <summary>Undoes the change.</summary>
      <exception cref="InvalidOperationException">
        Thrown if the change has not been applied yet, or if the document has
        been altered such that the change cannot be applied.
      </exception>
    </Undo>
  </ChangeEvent>
  
  <Document>
    <OnNodeChanged>
      <summary>
        Called when a node (or one of the node's descendants) that belongs to this document has changed
        such that it may need to be rerendered.
      </summary>
    </OnNodeChanged>  
  </Document>

  <DocumentEditor>
    <LayoutRegion>
      <Children>
        <summary>
          Gets an array containing the children of this region. Each child is a region that is contained within
          this region, both visually and document-wise.
        </summary>
      </Children>
    </LayoutRegion>

    <LayoutSpan>
      <LineCount>
        <summary>Gets the number of lines within the node's content, without considering the effects of line wrapping.</summary>
      </LineCount>
      
      <CreateNew>
        <summary>
          Returns a new <see cref="LayoutSpan"/> of the same type as this, referencing the same
          <see cref="DocumentNode"/>, but with all other fields at their default.
        </summary>
      </CreateNew>

      <GetNextSplitPiece>
        <summary>
          Assists the work of line wrapping by calculating how many document indices from the content line
          can fit in amount of horizontal space of the layout line.
        </summary>
        <param name="gdi">The graphics context.</param>
        <param name="line">The index of the current content line.</param>
        <param name="piece">
          The previous piece returned from this method, or null if this is the first call for the
          given content line.
        </param>
        <param name="spaceLeft">How much horizontal space is left in the current layout line, in pixels.</param>
        <param name="lineIsEmpty">Whether the current layout line is empty.</param>
        <returns>
          Returns a <see cref="SplitPiece"/> representing the size and length of the content that can fit on
          the layout line.
        </returns>
      </GetNextSplitPiece>

      <Render>
        <summary>Renders the span at the given point.</summary>
      </Render>
    </LayoutSpan>
  </DocumentEditor>
  
  <DocumentNode>
    <GetDescription>
      <summary>Gets a short description of this node.</summary>
      <remarks>
        For instance, a root node may return "document" and a node that represents a picture may return
        "Picture: ALT" where ALT represents the picture's alt text. This text will be displayed in the description of
        change events.
      </remarks>
    </GetDescription>

    <OnNodeChanged>
      <summary>Called when the node has changed substantially, such that it may need to be rerendered.</summary>
    </OnNodeChanged>
  </DocumentNode>

  <DocumentParser>
    <Parse>
      <summary>
        Given a stream containing document data, converts it to a new <see cref="Document"/> and returns the
        new document.
      </summary>
    </Parse>
  </DocumentParser>
  
  <EditableTextBuffer>
    <Indexer>
      <summary>Gets or sets the character at the given index.</summary>
    </Indexer>

    <Capacity>
      <summary>
        Gets or sets the maximum number of characters the buffer can hold. The capacity cannot be set lower
        than the current length.
      </summary>
    </Capacity>

    <Length>
      <summary>Gets the number of characters in the text buffer.</summary>
    </Length>

    <CopyTo2>
      <summary>Copies all of the text to the given array.</summary>
      <param name="destArray">The destination array.</param>
      <param name="destIndex">The index within <paramref name="destArray"/> at which to write the text.</param>
    </CopyTo2>

    <CopyTo3>
      <summary>
        Writes text from the text buffer to the given <see cref="TextWriter"/>.
      </summary>
      <param name="writer">The text writer to which the text will be written.</param>
      <param name="srcIndex">
        The starting index of the text to write to <paramref name="writer"/>.
      </param>
      <param name="count">
        The number of characters to write to <paramref name="writer"/>.
      </param>
    </CopyTo3>

    <CopyTo4>
      <summary>Copies characters from the buffer to the given character array.</summary>
      <include file="documentation.xml" path="/UI/EditableTextBuffer/CopyTo2/param"/>
      <param name="srcIndex">The starting index of the text to copy to <paramref name="destArray"/>.</param>
      <param name="count">The number of characters to copy.</param>
    </CopyTo4>

    <Delete>
      <summary>Deletes the character at the given index.</summary>
    </Delete>

    <Delete2>
      <summary>Deletes deletes the specified number of characters starting at the given index.</summary>
    </Delete2>

    <FindNext>
      <summary>Searches for the next occurence of the given character, starting from the given index.</summary>
      <param name="c">The character to search for.</param>
      <param name="startIndex">The index at which to begin the search.</param>
      <returns>Returns the index of the next occurence of the character, or -1 if it could not be found.</returns>
    </FindNext>

    <GetText>
      <summary>Retrieves all of the text in the text buffer.</summary>
    </GetText>

    <GetText2>
      <summary>
        Returns a string containing the given number of characters, starting at the given index, from the text
        buffer.
      </summary>
    </GetText2>

    <InsertChar>
      <summary>Inserts a character into text buffer at the given index.</summary>
    </InsertChar>

    <InsertArray>
      <summary>Inserts characters from a character array into the text buffer.</summary>
    </InsertArray>

    <InsertString>
      <summary>Inserts a string into the text buffer at the given index.</summary>
    </InsertString>

    <InsertReader>
      <summary>Inserts all text from the given <see cref="TextReader"/> into the text buffer.</summary>
    </InsertReader>
  </EditableTextBuffer>

  <LineStorage>
    <LineCount>
      <summary>Gets the number of lines stored.</summary>
    </LineCount>

    <CharToLine>
      <summary>Converts a character index to its line number.</summary>
    </CharToLine>

    <CharToLine2>
      <summary>Converts a character index to its line number and column.</summary>
    </CharToLine2>

    <GetLineInfo>
      <summary>Given a line number, returns its character offset and its length.</summary>
      <param name="line">The line number to query.</param>
      <param name="offset">Receives the character offset of the start of the line.</param>
      <param name="length">Receives the length of the line.</param>
    </GetLineInfo>

    <GetLineLength>
      <summary>Returns the length of the given line.</summary>
    </GetLineLength>

    <GetLineLengths>
      <summary>Returns an array containing the lengths of all lines.</summary>
    </GetLineLengths>
    
    <AddLine>
      <summary>Inserts a line at the end of the document with the given length.</summary>
    </AddLine>

    <AlterLength>
      <summary>Alters the length of a line, given a difference in length.</summary>
      <param name="line">The line number whose length will be altered.</param>
      <param name="lengthDelta">The difference in length, such as 1 to increase the length by 1, or -1 to decrease it.</param>
    </AlterLength>

    <Clear>
      <summary>Removes all lines.</summary>
    </Clear>

    <InsertLine>
      <summary>Inserts a line at the given index, with the given length.</summary>
    </InsertLine>

    <DeleteLine>
      <summary>Removes the given line.</summary>
    </DeleteLine>

    <SetAllLengths>
      <summary>Replaces all lines with the list of line lengths given.</summary>
    </SetAllLengths>

    <SetLength>
      <summary>Sets the length of a line to the given value.</summary>
    </SetLength>
  </LineStorage>

  <Style>
    <GetOption>
      <summary>Gets either the local or effective value of the given option.</summary>
      <typeparam name="T">The type of the option value.</typeparam>
      <param name="optionName">The name of the option.</param>
      <param name="searchAncestors">
        If true, the effective value will be returned. If false, the local value will be
        returned.
      </param>
    </GetOption>
    
    <SetOption>
      <summary>Sets or clears the local value of the given option.</summary>
      <typeparam name="T">The type of the option value.</typeparam>
      <param name="optionName">The name of the option.</param>
      <param name="value">
        The value of the option. If null, the local value will be cleared, allowing values from
        ancestors to cascade to this style. If non-null, the local value will be set.
      </param>
      <param name="triggerNodeChange">
        If true, <see cref="DocumentNode.OnNodeChanged"/> will be called on the owner
        node.
      </param>
    </SetOption>
  </Style>
</UI>